# Bianca F. Ribeiro

GROWER | IPM SCOUTER | AGRONOMIST

+55(41)992346425 biancaribs@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/biancafeitosa



#### About Me

Professional focused on crop quality, yield improvement, and profitability by maximizing aspects involved in plant growth, such as water quality, pest management, climate, and environmental control, fertilizer regime. Previously worked as a Grower at the South Central Growers in Tennesse, growing, submitting trials and research on new varieties of ornamentals species for large companies such as Syngenta, Ball, Pan American and Dummen Orange mainly, with the annual improvement of plants.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

#### SOUTH CENTRAL GROWERS- TN, USA

2022 - 2023

Responsible for growing and caring for a variety of annuals, perennials, flowers, and vegetable plants. Tasks include crop care, greenhouse management, pest control, and moisture control. Also involved in plant science activities such as improving crop recipes, conducting trials, and implementing Integrated Pest Management (IPM) techniques. Developed and executed large trials for major companies in the industry. Proficient in the application of chemicals and experienced in maintaining and analyzing environmental data in a high-tech greenhouse. Skilled in using office tools and applications.

Achievements include successful cost reduction through trials with new technologies, effective monitoring and interpretation of greenhouse parameters, and a good understanding of the market's needs and challenges.

### PLANTARTE- CURITIBA PR, BRAZIL

2018 - 2020

Agronomist seller in order to present services offered by the company Handling office programs (Word, Power Point, Excel, CAD) Product advice and which one is more appropriate in relation to the customer Contact with the stage of plant production, supply and horticulture. Main Results: Year-end goals achieved, loyalty of conquered customers and improvement of existing services substantially.

### LANGUAGES

- English: Fluent
- Spanish: Intermediate
- Portuguese: Native Speaker

#### SKILLS

- Integrate Pest
- Management
- Biological Control
- Pesticides
- Plant Nutrition
- Water quality
- Labor Management
- Presentations
- Team building
- Microsoft
- Research
- Planning
- Office Tools and
- Software

#### EDUCATION

### BA- Bachelor in Agronomy

Tuiuti University of Paraná – Agronomy (2018–2023)

### **Courses and Workshops**

"Improving Production via Listening to Plants" by Ohio State University, 2021.

English For Agronomists, specialization course on agriculture, technologies and international networking while learning English, 2019.

SENAR, genetic improvement, development management in agribusiness and finished cutting plants, 2019.